Dreyer family. Papers of the Dreyer family, 1778-1928: A Finding Aid
Papers of the Dreyer family 1778-1928
- Series III. THIRD GENERATION: CORRESPONDENCE, 1817-1881, n.d. (#1.15-6.7)
  - Subseries C. August Ferdinand Dreier (b.1808), 1830-1879 (#2.10-2.13)
    - August Ferdinand Dreier (b.1808) to Pastor Mueller, 1830-1831; re: news from several members of Dreier family; vacation of Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Uhthoff, b.1774) in southern Germany; business dealings; birthday wishes, 2.13.
  - Subseries D. Heinrich Eduard Dreier (b.1811) and Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) 1829-1881, n.d. (#2.14-3.4, 3.6-5.5, 6.4-6.7)
    - Heinrich Eduard Dreier (b.1811) to his mother Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Uhthoff, b.1774), 1829-1845, n.d.; re: birthday wishes; religious topics, 2.14.
    - Heinrich Eduard Dreier (b.1811) to his brother Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1831-1873, n.d., re: death of Gustav Theodor Dreier's daughter Sophie Henriette Dreier (b.1831); religious topics; birthday wishes; his work as pastor; books, 2.15
    - Heinrich Eduard Dreier (b.1811) to his daughter Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1856-1869; re: poems refering to marriage between her and her cousin Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828); emigration of couple to United States; work as pastor; family celebrations; birthday wishes; war between Prussia and Hanover (1866); disease of one of his granddaughters, 2.16.
    - Heinrich Eduard Dreier (b.1811) to his daughter Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1870-1881, n.d.; re: work as pastor; family celebrations; birthday wishes; Franco-Prussian War (1870-1871), 2.17.
    - Heinrich Eduard Dreier (b.1811) to his nephew and son-in-law Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828), 1845-1879; re: work of his son Johann Caspar Ludwig Dreier (b.1843) in United States; work as pastor; family celebrations, 2.18.
    - Heinrich Eduard Dreier (b.1811) to his daughter Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840) and his nephew and son-in-law Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828), two letters also addressed to his son Johann Caspar Ludwig Dreier (b.1843), 1865-1881, n.d., re: departure of couple to United States and domiciles in United States; job for his son Johann Caspar Ludwig Dreier (b.1843); family celebrations; religious topics; Civil War; poems; religious care for Germans in United States by German pastors; cure in Bad Ems; birth and death of grandchildren; work as pastor, 3.1.
    - Heinrich Eduard Dreier (b.1811) to his son Johann Caspar Ludwig Dreier (b.1843), 1863; re: death of a relative, 3.2.
    - Heinrich Eduard Dreier (b.1811) to his mother-in-law Mrs. Hotzen, 1841-1854, n.d.; re: marriage settlement between him and his wife Margaretha (Meta) Thibeta Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817); visit and appraisal of schools in Stetten and Korntal; condition of Margaretha (Meta) Thibeta Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) after birth, 3.3.
    - Heinrich Eduard Dreier (b.1811) to his sister-in-law Thaddea Henriette Dreier (née Schacht, b. 1806), 1831-1834; re: condition and treatment of friend of Thaddea Henriette Dreier, suffering of mental disorder, 3.4.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her mother Mrs. Hotzen, some with transcription in German, 1835-1837; re: life and education at her grandmother's home; social events, 3.6.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her mother Mrs. Hotzen, some with transcription in German, 1838; re: marriage with Heinrich Eduard Dreier (b.1811); appeal for Mrs. Hotzen's advive concerning Dreier's proposal; refused proposal, 3.7.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her mother Mrs. Hotzen, 1839; re: pregnancy and her husband's reactions; physical and mental condition during pregnancy; domestics; career of her husband as pastor; birth of daughter Margaretha (Meta); life with newborn child, 3.8.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her mother Mrs. Hotzen, 1840; re: life with newborn child; relationship between father and child; conflicts because of ordination of her husband as pastor; second pregnancy; difficult birth of second child Dorothea Adelheid and physical condition afterwards, 3.9.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her mother Mrs. Hotzen, 1841; re: flood of river Weser; breastfeeding, 3.10.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her mother Mrs. Hotzen, 1842; re: disease of second child and treatment with emetic and leeches; controversial election of her husband as preacher; third pregnancy, 3.11.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her mother Mrs. Hotzen, 1843; re: agony and death of friend's child; employment of nanny; third pregnancy and birth of Johann Caspar Ludwig; assumed hernia of new born baby and treatment, 3.12.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her mother Mrs. Hotzen, 1844; re: education of children; social life in village; rectorates and pastors; presumed croup of one daughter, 3.13.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her mother Mrs. Hotzen, 1845; re: social life in village; condition of children and of mother-in-law; gardening, 3.14.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her mother Mrs. Hotzen, 1846; re: presumed croup of son; condition of children and mother-in-law; abscess in oral cavity of her husband and treatment; several cases of death in village; possible move because of job change of husband, 3.15.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her mother Mrs. Hotzen, 1847; re: clothing; vain efforts of her husband to get a rectorate; measles epidemic; inheritance from mother-in-law; nanny; agony and death of friend, 3.16.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her mother Mrs. Hotzen, 1848; re: profession of husband as pastor; precaution against revolution in village; fear of war; concern about brother in army; quartering of soldier in her house; care for widow of pastor, 3.17.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her mother Mrs. Hotzen, 1849; re: agony and death of widow in village and care for her four children; adoption of one of them as foster child; concerns about health of members of own family; profession of husband as pastor, 3.18.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her mother Mrs. Hotzen, 1850; re: teacher for children; rectorate for her husband; move to Bremerhaven; also includes letters from children to their grandmother, 3.19.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her mother Mrs. Hotzen, 1851; re: new position of husband; social life; schooling of foster child Carl Radatz, 3.20.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her mother Mrs. Hotzen, 1852; re: problems concerning schooling and education of children; new home; education of child at home of grandmother, 3.21.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her mother Mrs. Hotzen, 1853; re: problems with housemaid; schooling of children; further future of foster child; financial problems of her brother-in-law Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803); cholera epidemic among emigrants in Bremerhaven and a nearby town, 3.22.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her mother Mrs. Hotzen, 1854; re: education and schooling of children; work of husband, 3.23.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her mother Mrs. Hotzen, 1855; re: work of husband; future careers of son and foster child; education of son, 3.24.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her mother Mrs. Hotzen, 1856; re: professional future of husband; his work at House of Emigrants (Auswandererhaus) in Bremerhaven and his unsuccessful job applications; further education of second daughter; possible savings in household; critical remarks on marriage of brother; new position of husband and move to Blumenthal, 3.25.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her mother Mrs. Hotzen, 1857; re: son's problems in school and his future career, 3.26.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her mother Mrs. Hotzen, 1858; re: possible housing of orphan and her schooling by Mrs. Dreier's eldest daughter; housemaid; schooling of son, 3.27.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her mother Mrs. Hotzen, 1859; re: future of foster child; female boarders/housemaids, 3.28.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her mother Mrs. Hotzen, 1860; re: time-consuming housework, 3.29.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her mother Mrs. Hotzen, 1861; re: difficult financial situation of family; dowry of eldest daughter; plea for payback of debts; marriage of eldest daughter and her marital life; children of her son-in-law from his first marriage; pregnancy of eldest daughter; new rectorate of husband; description of new manse, 3.30.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her mother Mrs. Hotzen, 1862; re: birth of granddaughter; housemaid, 3.31.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her mother Mrs. Hotzen, n.d., 3.32
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her mother-in-law Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Uhthoff, b.1774), 1839, 1842; re: birthday wishes, 3.33.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her sister Marie, 1837, 3.34.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her brother-in-law Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803) and her sister-in-law Thaddea Henriette Dreier (née Schacht, b.1806), 1855, 1857, 1870; re: care and death of Thaddea Henriette Dreier's son Julius Alexander Dreier (b.1838), 3.35.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her daughter Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1853-1856, 3.36.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her daughter Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1857-1860; re: charity; stays of her daughter at homes of several friends and relatives; housework, 3.37.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her daughter Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1861-1864; re: life after eldest daughter Margaretha (Meta) had married and left house; travels; housework, 4.1.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her daughter Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1865; re: disease of husband; arrival of her son Johann Caspar Ludwig Dreier (b.1843) in United States; clothing etc. for grandchild; birth of granddaughter Margaretha Henriette, 4.2.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her daughter Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1866; re: literature; conflict between Hanover and Prussia; disease and death of granddaughter, 4.3.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her daughter Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1867; re: birth of grandson Johann Caspar Theodor; situation in Hanover after it became part of Prussia, 4.4.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her daughter Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1868; re: aging of husband; incidents in village; work of son in United States; birth of granddaughter Margaretha (Gretchen), 4.5.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her daughter Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1869; re: death of grandson; reading; refusal of planned visit at daughter's home in United States; planned trip of daughter and son-in-law to Germany; sympathy for discharged king of Hanover; work of son in United States, 4.6.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her daughter Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1870; re: credit of son-in-law for other son-in-law; fosteraging ill foster child in Montreux; wearing of mourning; failure of son's business in United States; birth of granddaughter Dorothea Adelheid; presumable miscarriage of other daughter Margaretha (Meta), 4.7.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her daughter Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1871; re: disease of her brother-in-law Julius Alexander Dreier (b.1805); disease, agony and death of child of other daughter Margaretha (Meta); Franco-Prussian War (1870-1871); workload because of household and boarders, 4.8.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her daughter Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1872; re: housemaid; birth of fifth child of daughter (Heinrich Eduard) and possible illness of other daughter Margaretha (Meta) because of 10th pregnancy; emigration of men to United States to avoid military service; parcels with clothing from United States, 4.9.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her daughter Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1873; re: disease and death of brother-in-law Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803) and future of his housekeeper; visit at daughter's home in United States, 4.10.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her daughter Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1874; re: situation in household of other daughter Margaretha (Meta) after birth of 8th child; situation of Catholics in Hanover; implementation of civil marriage; trip of daughter and son-in-law to Europe; poems, 4.11.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her daughter Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1875; re: death of friend from typhus; condition of husband; trip of son to Germany; sinking of steamboat "Schiller"; birth of 6th child of daughter (Maria (Mary) Elisabeth), 4.12.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her daughter Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1876; re: situation in household of other daughter Margaretha (Meta); condition of former foster child in sanatorium in Badenweiler; delivery of fruits from daughter and son-in-law to Germany, 4.13.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her daughter Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1877; re: birth of 7th child of daughter (Katherine Sophie); children of other daughter Margaretha (Meta); professional situation of son in United States; condition of former foster child in Switzerland; death of Bertha Dreier (née Obermann, b.1846) and care for her children, 4.14.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her daughter Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1878; re: aging; advice for pregnant daughter and stillbirth of her child, 5.1.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her daughter Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1879; re: physical condition of former foster child; daughter's and son-in-law's care for parentless girl; move of family of other daughter Margaretha (Meta) to Giessen and situation at her home, 5.2.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her daughter Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1880; re: aging; death of former foster child Carl Radatz, 5.3.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her daughter Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1881; re: trip of daughter and son-in-law to Europe with cure in Karlsbad and schooling and education of children during that time, 5.4.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her daughter Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), n.d.; re: delivery of cans with fruits and vegetables to United States, 5.5.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her daughter Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), her son-in-law Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) and her son Johann Caspar Ludwig Dreier (b.1843), 1876, 6.4.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her nephew and son-in-law Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828), 1867-1879, n.d.; includes mainly; birthday wishes, 6.5.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) to her niece Dorothea Henriette Christine Dreier (b.1829), 1861, 6.6.
    - To Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) from different persons, 1865-1877, n.d., 6.7.
- Series IV. FOURTH GENERATION: CORRESPONDENCE, 1837-1893, n.d. (#6.8-14.3)
  Series IV, FOURTH GENERATION: CORRESPONDENCE, 1837-1893, n.d., (#6.8-14.3), contains correspondence of the children of the four sons of Johann Caspar Dreier (formerly Dreyer, b.1758) and Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Uhthoff, b.1774) and their spouses.
  - Subseries A. Children of Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803) and Thaddea Henriette Dreier (née Schacht, b.1806) and their spouses, 1837-1881, n.d. (#6.8-11.11, 13.9)
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his grandmother Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Uhthoff, b.1774), 1843, 6.8.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1837-1844, 6.9.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1850; re: work at Naylor Co. (steel distributor), New York, 6.10.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1851; re: business in United States, 6.11.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1852; re: financial problems of father, 6.12.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1853; re: financial problems of father, probable sale of parents' house, 6.13.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1854; re: work in United States, 6.14.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1855; re: work in United States; business, 6.15.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1856; re: travel to Great Lakes, Canada, and Niagara Falls; recently constructed Niagara Falls suspension bridge; financial situation of family in Bremen; work in United States, 6.16.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1857; re: death of brother Julius Alexander Dreier (b.1838); work in United States; business; life at East coast, 6.17.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1858; re: travels to Niagara Falls and Great Britain, 6.18.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1859; re: physical condition of his sister Dorothea Henriette Christine Dreier (b.1829) and his mother Thaddea Henriette Dreier (née Schacht, b.1806); travels to Ohio, Pennsylvania, Wisconsin and Illinois; financial situation of father, 6.19.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1860; re: death of mother, 6.20.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1861; re: outbreak of Civil War; economic consequences of war; business, 6.21.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1862; re: Civil War; Mason and Slidell Affair; economic consequences of war; military operations, 7.1.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1863; re: arrival of his brother Karl Wilhelm Dreier (b.1836) in New York; Karl's conduct and his pretended engagement; Civil War; business, 7.2.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1864; re: honeymoon with Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840) in England; new home of couple in Brooklyn, 7.3.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1865; re: first pregnancy of wife; job for his cousin Johann Caspar Ludwig Dreier (b.1843) in United States, 7.4.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1866; re: death of daughter Margaretha Henriette from an influenza infection, 7.5.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1867; re: birth of second child Johann Caspar Theodor, 7.6.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1868; re: situation of his brother Karl Wilhelm Dreier (b.1836) in United States and as farmer in Midwest; birth of third child Margaretha (Gretchen); engagement of his uncle August Ferdinand Dreier (b.1808) to Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Meinertzhagen (b.1814), 7.7.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1869; re: death of second child Johann Caspar Theodor; travel by rail to Niagara Falls; physical condition of his sister Dorothea Henriette Christine Dreier (b.1829); payments to his brother Karl Wilhelm Dreier (b.1836), 7.8.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1870; re: birth of fourth child Dorothea Adelheid; physical condition and death of his sister Dorothea Henriette Christine Dreier (b.1829); Franco-Prussian War (1870-1871), 8.1.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1871; re: travel of father to United States, 8.2.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1872; re: modification and interior of house; birth of fifth child Heinrich Eduard, 8.3.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), n.d., 8.4.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his mother Thaddea Henriette Dreier (née Schacht, b.1806), 1845-1860, n.d., 8.5.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his father-in-law Heinrich Eduard Dreier (b.1811), 1869; re: business conduct of his brother-in-law Johann Caspar Ludwig Dreier (b.1843), 13.9.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his wife Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1864-1867, n.d., 8.6.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his wife Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1869-1870, 8.7.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his wife Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1871; some letters in English, 8.8.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his wife Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1872, 8.9.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his wife Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1873, 8.10.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his wife Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1874; re: travel of wife and children to parents and relatives in Germany; cure of wife in Karlsbad, 9.1.-9.4.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his wife Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1875, 9.5.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his wife Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1876, 9.6.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his wife Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1877, 9.7.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his wife Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1878; re: travel to Germany and Austria; cure in Karlsbad (3 folders), 9.8-10.1.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his wife Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1881, 10.2.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his wife Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), n.d., 10.3
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his sister Dorothea Henriette Christine Dreier (b.1829), 1861-1870; re: sister's disease, 10.4.